<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Doing GitOps with Flux v2 on Weaveworks Introduction to GitOps w/ AWS EKS</title>
    <link>/22_workshop_1/30_gitops_enable.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Doing GitOps with Flux v2 on Weaveworks Introduction to GitOps w/ AWS EKS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/22_workshop_1/30_gitops_enable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing the configuration repo</title>
      <link>/22_workshop_1/30_gitops_enable/33_using_flux_v2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/22_workshop_1/30_gitops_enable/33_using_flux_v2.html</guid>
      <description>You have created an EKS cluster, installed Flux v2 in it, and created a repo that holds manifests matching precisely the current state of your cluster -and you did all that with one command, pretty cool right!.
In order to manage your cluster as well as deploy workloads you will need to clone the repo that Flux v2 created in your GitHub account. Flux created and configured a key pair for the repository automatically, and uses it to provide repository access to the Source Controller running in the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing configuration with GitOps</title>
      <link>/22_workshop_1/30_gitops_enable/34_update_flux_for_demo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/22_workshop_1/30_gitops_enable/34_update_flux_for_demo.html</guid>
      <description>Lets look at how configuration is managed following GitOps by modifying declarations in the repository created by Flux v2.
To demonstrate this, you will change the default polling interval configured by Flux in the Kustomization that pulls changes from the ./clusters/aws-workshop path in the repository. This change will also help accelerate changes being applied to the cluster, which will make the demo go smoother.
First, check the current configuration as applied to the cluster, by running the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>