<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prerequisites for Workshop on Weaveworks Introduction to GitOps w/ AWS EKS</title>
    <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prerequisites for Workshop on Weaveworks Introduction to GitOps w/ AWS EKS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Workspace</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/10_workspace.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/10_workspace.html</guid>
      <description>AWS Cloud9 is a cloud-based integrated development environment (IDE) that lets you write, run, and debug your code with just a browser. It includes a code editor, debugger, and terminal. Cloud9 comes prepackaged with essential tools for popular programming languages, including JavaScript, Python, PHP, and more, so you don’t need to install files or configure your development machine to start new projects.
 Ad blockers, javascript disablers, and tracking blockers should be disabled for the cloud9 domain, or connecting to the workspace might be impacted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add the Required IAM Role</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/11_add_the_role.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/11_add_the_role.html</guid>
      <description>Creating and using EKS clusters in AWS requires specific IAM roles for the user creating and accessing EKS clusters.
Create admin role  Switch to the AWS Console (You can open the console from the &amp;ldquo;Team Dashboard&amp;rdquo;) Under Services, select IAM &amp;gt; Roles &amp;gt; Create Role Confirm that AWS service and EC2 are selected, then click Next to view permissions. Confirm that AdministratorAccess is checked, then click Next: Tags to assign tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install AWS IAM</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/12_install_aws-iam.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/12_install_aws-iam.html</guid>
      <description>Amazon EKS uses IAM to provide authentication to your Kubernetes cluster through the AWS IAM authenticator for Kubernetes. You can configure the stock kubectl client to work with Amazon EKS by installing the AWS IAM authenticator for Kubernetes and modifying your kubectl configuration file to use it for authentication.
To install aws-iam-authenticator on Cloud9
Download the Amazon EKS-vended aws-iam-authenticator binary from Amazon S3:
curl -o aws-iam-authenticator https://amazon-eks.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1.15.10/2020-02-22/bin/linux/amd64/aws-iam-authenticator chmod +x ./aws-iam-authenticator sudo mv .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update IAM settings for your Workspace</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/13_workspaceiam.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/13_workspaceiam.html</guid>
      <description>Cloud9 normally manages IAM credentials dynamically. This isn&amp;rsquo;t currently compatible with the EKS IAM authentication, so we will disable it and rely on the IAM role instead.
  Return to your workspace and click the gear icon (in top right corner), or click to open a new tab and choose &amp;ldquo;Open Preferences&amp;rdquo; Select AWS SETTINGS Turn off AWS managed temporary credentials Close the Preferences tab   To ensure temporary credentials aren&amp;rsquo;t already in place we will also remove any existing credentials file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install eksctl</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/14_install_eksctl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/14_install_eksctl.html</guid>
      <description>For this workshop you will use a eksctl. Once you install eksctl, you will be ready to get started.
At the terminal command prompt, enter the following two commands:
curl --silent --location &amp;#34;https://github.com/weaveworks/eksctl/releases/latest/download/eksctl_$(uname -s)_amd64.tar.gz&amp;#34; | tar xz -C /tmp sudo mv /tmp/eksctl /usr/local/bin This will install eksctl in your Cloud9 environment. To test to make sure the command is installed properly, execute the command:
eksctl version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create EKS cluster</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/15_create_eks_cluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/15_create_eks_cluster.html</guid>
      <description>Create EKS Cluster  In a seperate terminal, run
eksctl create cluster --version 1.17 --nodes 1 -t t3.large my-management-cluster  This will save us time while we go through next steps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install kubectl</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/16_install_kubectl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/16_install_kubectl.html</guid>
      <description>The Kubernetes command-line tool, kubectl, allows you to run commands against Kubernetes clusters. You can use kubectl to deploy applications, inspect and manage cluster resources, and view logs.
At the terminal command prompt, enter the following two commands:
curl -LO https://storage.googleapis.com/kubernetes-release/release/`curl -s https://storage.googleapis.com/kubernetes-release/release/stable.txt`/bin/linux/amd64/kubectl chmod +x ./kubectl sudo mv ./kubectl /usr/local/bin/kubectl This will install kubectl in your Cloud9 environment. To test to make sure the command is installed properly, execute the command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install helm</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/17_install_helm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/17_install_helm.html</guid>
      <description>Helm describes itself as a &amp;lsquo;package manager for kubernetes&amp;rsquo; and can be used to deploy resources to Kubernetes.
You package your application as a chart which can contain templated files (usually Kubernetes resources) and default configuration values too use when rendering the template. Charts are reusable and values can be overriden for specific environments.
We are using Helm v3 in the workshops. So there is no tiller. If you are using your own environment and not the workshops Cloud9 environment and you have Helm v2 the commands should work ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install fluxctl</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/18_install_fluxctl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/18_install_fluxctl.html</guid>
      <description> Install Fluxctl Fluxctl is a CLI tool that is able to talk to Weave Flux.
Install by running this command:
curl -Ls https://fluxcd.io/install | sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ sudo mv $HOME/.fluxcd/bin/fluxctl /usr/local/bin/fluxctl Verify the installation:
fluxctl version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install direnv</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/19_direnv.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/19_direnv.html</guid>
      <description>direnv takes care of exporting environment variables automatically based on the directory we&amp;rsquo;re in.
To install direnv, run the following commands.
curl -sfL https://direnv.net/install.sh | bash echo &amp;#34;eval &amp;#39;$(direnv hook bash)&amp;#39;&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc source ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install clusterctl</title>
      <link>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/20_clusterctl.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/70_workshop_7_multicloud/10_prerequisites/20_clusterctl.html</guid>
      <description>The CluserAPI (CAPI) is a project of SIG Cluster Lifecycle to bring declarative, Kubernetes-style APIs to cluster creation, configuration, and management.
cluserctl is the cli that we&amp;rsquo;ll use to bootstrap the CAPI controllers.
curl -L https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/cluster-api/releases/download/v0.3.6/clusterctl-linux-amd64 -o clusterctl chmod +x ./clusterctl sudo mv ./clusterctl /usr/local/bin/clusterctl Validate that it&amp;rsquo;s working
clusterctl version</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>